A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of Communications, Program Staff Files FA636
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Office of Communications, Program Staff Files
1955-1980
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA636
26.84 Cubic Feet
23 boxes. Two document size boxes -- No. 7 & 16.
Conditions Governing Access note
Material is open for scholarly research, with prior archival review.
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.
Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment. Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Ford Foundation
- Fred Friendly Office Files, 1959-1980; I
  - Fred Friendly Office Files -- Subject files, 1959-1970; I.1
    - AT&T, 1966-1968 (Box 1)
    - BBC, 1965-1967 (Box 1)
    - Bibliography on the Economics of Television -- Marshall A. Robinson, 1966 (Box 1)
    - B -- Miscellaneous, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
    - CATV -- Incl. Information on Construction of the World Trade Center and its Effect on Television Reception in New York City, 1966-1968 (Box 1)
    - CATV -- FCC Dockets Re: FCC Regulations, 1969 (Box 1)
    - CATV -- FCC Regulations, 1969 (Box 1)
    - CATV -- General, 1968 (Box 1)
    - CATV -- Rand Study, 1969 (Box 1)
    - CATV -- Report, "An Industry Report on Community Antenna Television" by Drexel Harriman Ripley, Inc., Oct 15, 1968 (Box 1)
    - CATV -- Television Digest's 1969 35-Mile Zone Map Book (Box 1)
    - CATV for Harlem -- Thomas Vietorisz Proposal, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Coase, Ronald -- Report, "Educational Television: Who Should Pay?", 1967-1968 (Box 1)
    - "Commercial Television Properties: A Programming Resource for Instructional Television?" -- Report, Apr 1, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Communications Satellite System -- Agreement Between U.S. and Other Governments -- Washington, DC, Aug 20, 1964 (Box 1)
    - Communications Satellite System -- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Complan Associates, Inc. -- Communications Consulting, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Cowan, Louis -- Thoughts and Proposal Re: Educational Television, 1963-1965 (Box 1)
    - Doan, Richard K. (TV Guide) -- Remarks at NAEB, Nov 8, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Ehrlich, Thomas -- Consultant, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
    - Eight Community Stations Statement for the Ford Foundation, 1966-1968 (Box 1)
    - ETS/ETV Program Service, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
    - ETV -- Consultants, 1962-1963 (Box 1)
    - ETV -- Facilities Act Grants -- Department of Health, Education and Welfare Memorandum, Jul 11, 1966 (Box 1)
    - ETV -- General, 1968 (Box 2)
    - ETV in the Ghetto, 1968 (Box 2)
    - ETV Stations on the Air, 1955-November 1967, 1966-1967 (Box 2)
    - ETV Stations -- Alabama, 1965-1966 (Box 2)
    - ETV Stations -- Arkansas, 1967 (Box 2)
    - ETV Stations -- California, 1966-1967 (Box 2)
    - ETV Stations -- Florida, 1965-1967 (Box 2)
    - ETV Stations -- Kansas, 1965-1967 (Box 2)
    - ETV Stations -- Kentucky, 1965-1967 (Box 2)
    - ETV Stations -- Nebraska, 1965-1967 (Box 2)
    - ETV Stations -- New Hampshire, 1965-1967 (Box 2)
    - ETV Stations -- New York, 1965-1967 (Box 2)
    - ETV Stations -- Ohio, 1965-1967 (Box 2)
    - ETV Stations -- Rhode Island, 1967 (Box 2)
    - ETV Stations -- Virginia, 1965-1967 (Box 2)
    - Federal Communications Committee (FCC) -- ABC, 1967 (Box 2)
    - FCC -- AT&T Network Rates, 1967-1968 (Box 2)
    - FCC -- CATV and the Ford Foundation, 1969 (Box 2)
    - FCC -- Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 2)
    - FCC -- First Amendment -- Correspondence, 1969 (Box 2)
    - FCC -- Speeches, 1967-1969 (Box 2)
    - Film Library -- Proposal for National Television News Archive, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Ford Foundation -- Dedication (December 8, 1967), 1967-1968 (Box 2)
    - Ford Foundation -- Dining Room Expenses, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
    - Ford Foundation -- Policies, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Ford Foundation -- Tax Legislation, 1969 (Box 2)
    - Foreign Correspondence, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Ginsburg, David and Lee Marks (law office), 1967-1969 (Box 2)
    - Goldin, Hy, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
    - Government Departments -- Senate, House, Bureaus -- Correspondence, 1967 (Box 2)
    - International Broadcast Institute (IBI), 1967-1968 (Box 2)
    - Institute of International Education (IIE), 1961-1968 (Box 2)
    - Immaculate Heart, 1967 (Box 2)
    - Invitations -- Accepted, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
    - Invitations -- Declined (sampling of letters), 1967-1968 (Box 2)
    - Levin, Harvey -- Re: Broadcast Regulation, 1967-1969 (Box 2)
    - Memos -- Bell -- Re: Ford Foundation Work Overseas and Foundation Program Reports, 1967-1969 (Box 3)
    - Memos -- Bundy -- Personal and Professional Re: Ford Foundation Work, Public Broadcasting, Letter from Lillian Hellman, etc., 1967-1969 (Box 3)
    - Memos -- Budget -- Re: Office of Public Broadcasting, Incl. Reports, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
    - Memos -- Catalano, Dick -- Letters by Catalano for Fred Friendly, 1968 (Box 3)
    - Memos -- Catalano, 1967-1969 (Box 3)
    - Memos -- Catalano and Davis, 1967-1969 (Box 3)
    - Memos -- Davis, 1967-1969 (Box 3)
    - Memos -- Davis, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
    - Memos -- Davis Letters, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
    - Memos -- Davis Studio Visits, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
    - Memos -- Dressner, 1967-1969 (Box 3)
    - Memos -- Friendly, 1967-1969 (Box 3)
    - Memos -- Goldmann, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
    - Memos -- Jaffee -- Incl. Information Paper on Communications, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
    - Memos -- Magat, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
    - Memos -- Meade -- Incl. Possible Original Proposal for Sesame Street, 1967-1969 (Box 3)
    - Memos -- Slater, Jerry, 1969 (Box 3)
    - Memos -- Staff Meetings, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
    - Memos -- Sucherman, 1969 (Box 3)
    - Memos -- Sviridoff, 1967-1969 (Box 3)
    - Memos -- Ward, Champ -- Incl. Bill Cosby and Sesame Street Notes, 1967-1969 (Box 3)
    - Memos -- Miscellaneous, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
    - Minow, Newton -- Educational TV Article in Playboy Magazine, 1968 (Box 3)
    - Moynihan, Daniel P. -- Incl. Report, "The City in Chassis", 1968-1969 (Box 3)
    - National Advisory Commission on Civil Disorders, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
    - National Association of Educational Broadcasters (NAEB) -- Incl. "World Without Distance" Speech by Fred Friendly, 1967-1968 (Box 3)
    - National Citizens Committee for Broadcasting -- Kubasik, etc., 1968-1969 (Box 4)
    - Night Call -- Ford Foundation Support, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
    - One Nation Indivisible -- Evaluation Report, 1968-1970 (Box 4)
    - Public Broadcast Laboratory (PBL) -- Bohen -- Correspondence, Reports, Addresses, etc., 1968-1969 (Box 4)
    - PBL -- Budget, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
    - PBL -- Correspondence, 1967 (Box 4)
    - PBL -- Correspondence -- General, 1967-1968 (Box 4)
    - PBL -- Editorial Board, 1967-1969 (Box 4)
    - PBL -- Evaluators, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
    - PBL -- Fischer, John, 1967 (Box 4)
    - PBL -- Friendly, Fred, 1967-1968 (Box 4)
    - PBL -- Morgan, Edward, 1967-1969 (Box 4)
    - PBL -- PBS -- Memo Re: Establishment of PBS, Mar 10, 1969 (Box 4)
    - PBL -- Producers' Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 4)
    - PBL -- Miscellaneous Incl. List of Staff Members, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
    - PBL -- Producers Proposals, 1969 (Box 4)
    - PBL -- Promotion of Educational Television -- Grossman, Lawrence Incl. ETV Program Photographs, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
    - PBL -- Publicity, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
    - PBL -- Svetlana Alliluyeva, 1967 (Box 4)
    - PBL -- Westin, Av, 1967-1969 (Box 4)
    - Personnel, 1969 (Box 4)
    - Pratt, Gerry Re: Manuscript Submission, 1969-1970 (Box 4)
    - Proposals -- Miscellaneous Re: Educational Television, 1967-1969 (Box 4)
    - Reavis, John Re: Criticism of NET, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
    - Rickover, Rr. Adm. H.G. -- Incl. Correspondence Written During/About the First Transpolar Voyage, 1959-1967 (Box 4)
    - Rosner Television and TV Broadcasting from World Trade Center, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
    - Satellites (folder 1), 1969 (Box 4)
    - Satellites (folder 2), 1969 (Box 5)
    - Satellites (folder 3), 1969 (Box 5)
    - Satellites -- Domestic, 1969 (Box 5)
    - Satellites -- EDUSAT, 1969 (Box 5)
    - Satellites -- Latin American Material, 1969 (Box 5)
    - Satellite Communications -- Analysis of Domestic Satellite Communications in the U.S. -- Thesis by Stuart N. Goodman, Jun 1968 (Box 5)
    - Satellite Proposal and Senate Hearings -- Ford Foundation, 1968-1969 (Box 5)
    - Scheuer, Steve, 1968 (Box 5)
    - Scripts -- Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box 5)
    - Speaker Service -- Re: Friendly Speaking Engagements (one memo), 1969 (Box 5)
  - Fred Friendly Office Files -- Public/Educational Television and Miscellaneous Files (not arranged in Friendly's alpha subject files prior to processing), 1963-1972; I.2
    - American Research Bureau -- Television Overnight Survey Prepared for the Ford Foundation (sampling of surveys), Dec 1968 (Box 5)
    - Bedford Stuyvesant Restoration -- Cable Television Project, 1971 (Box 5)
    - Corporation for Public Broadcasting -- Annual Report, 1971 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, Reports, Lecture Requests, etc. Re: Public and Educational Television (folder 1), 1968-1969 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, Reports, Lecture Requests, etc. Re: Public and Educational Television (folder 2), 1968-1969 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, Reports, Lecture Requests, etc. Re: Public and Educational Television (folder 3), 1968-1969 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, Reports, Lecture Requests, etc. Re: Public and Educational Television (folder 4), 1968-1969 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, Reports, Lecture Requests, etc. Re: Public and Educational Television (folder 5), 1968-1969 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, Reports, Press Releases, Recommendations for Grant Actions, Budget Planning Reports, etc. Re: Public and Educational Television (folder 1), 1968-1969 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, Reports, Press Releases, Recommendations for Grant Actions, Budget Planning Reports, etc. Re: Public and Educational Television (folder 2), 1968-1969 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, Reports, Press Releases, Recommendations for Grant Actions, Budget Planning Reports, etc. Re: Public and Educational Television (folder 3), 1968-1969 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, Reports, Newspaper Articles Re: Television, Public Broadcasting, etc., 1968 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence -- Fred Friendly Personal, 1969 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence -- Miscellaneous, 1967 (Box 6)
    - Dayton, Ohio CATV Reports, 1971 (Box 6)
    - (The) Greater Cincinnati Television Educational Foundation -- Annual Report, 1967 (Box 6)
    - JCET News -- Monthly Publication Re: CATV, Jul-Dec 1971 (Box 6)
    - KQED Local Programming Grant Request, 1972 (Box 6)
    - Media and the 1968 Election -- Correspondence, Articles, etc. (Box 6)
    - New York State Public Utilities Commission Report on CATV, Dec 1970 (Box 6)
    - Political Process -- Ford/Carnegie Electoral Process Meeting, 1969 (Box 6)
    - Project for New Television Programming -- The Ford Foundation (materials removed from binder with folder title as label), 1969 (Box 6)
    - Public Broadcast Laboratory Consultants, 1967 (Box 6)
    - "Public Television: Financial Information" Report to the Ford Foundation from Arthur D. Little, Inc., Mar 1969 (Box 6)
    - Thompson, Kenneth W. -- Re: Alan Gregg, Incl. Gregg Memorial Lecture and List of Publications, 1968-1969 (Box 6)
    - "Utilization of the Regents Educational Television Broadcast Programs" Report (research sponsored by the Ford Foundation), Sep 1963 (Box 6)
    - Washington, D.C. Rand Study Re: CATV -- Mitre Corp. Reports, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Fred Friendly Office Files -- Ford Foundation Reports, 1967-1972; I.3 (Box 7)
    Arrangement
    Chronological
    - "Public Broadcast Laboratory of NET", Jun 1967 (Box 7)
    - "The Ford Foundation and Noncommercial Television", Dec 1967 (Box 7)
    - "ETV Local and Regional Programming", Mar 1968 (Box 7)
    - "International Division, Proposed Budget, Fiscal Year 1969", Jun 1968 (Box 7)
    - "National Affairs Division, Proposed Budget, Fiscal Year 1969", Jun 1968 (Box 7)
    - "Management Costs", Sep 1968 (Box 7)
    - "New Options in the Philanthropic Process" (published booklet), Sep 1968 (Box 7)
    - "Public Television Audience Research Working Seminar", Apr 12-13, 1971 (Box 7)
    - "Washington, D.C. Newsroom" -- Ford Foundation Office of Public Broadcasting, May 1971 (Box 7)
    - "Public Access: The Taped Nation" An Evaluation for the Ford Foundation by Richard Burgheim, Aug 20, 1972 (Box 7)
    - Draft of Report Re: Public Access (may be draft of "Public Access: The Taped Nation"), n.d. (Box 7)
  - Fred Friendly Office Files -- Meeting Transcripts, 1973-1980; I.4
    - Broadcasting and the First Amendment (folder 1), Jan 30-31, 1973 (Box 8)
    - Broadcasting and the First Amendment (folder 2), Jan 31, 1973 (Box 8)
    - C.E.E. Conference (Rome, Italy), Apr 6-7, 1973 (Box 8)
    - New England Conference on Conflicts Between the Media and the Law (Chatham, MA), Jun 7-9, 1974 (Box 8)
    - Book Publishing and the First Amendment (Southbury, CT), Apr 18-20, 1975 (Box 8)
    - Chicago Conference on the Media and the Law (folder 1), Sep 12-14, 1975 (Box 8)
    - Chicago Conference on the Media and the Law (folder 2), Sep 12-14, 1975 (Box 8)
    - Florida Conference on the Media and the Law (Key Biscayne, FL) -- Discussion Leader, Charles Nesson and Corrections to Transcript, Jun 19, 1976 (Box 8)
    - Florida Conference on the Media and the Law (Key Biscayne, FL) -- Discussion Leader, Arthur Miller, Jun 19, 1976 (Box 8)
    - Florida Conference on the Media and the Law (Key Biscayne, FL) -- Discussion Leader, Benno Schmidt, Jun 20, 1976 (Box 8)
    - West Virginia Conference on the Media and the Law (White Sulphur Springs, WV) -- Discussion Leaders, Nesson, Schauer, Miller, Dec 4-5, 1976 (Box 8)
    - News and the Law, Anglo-American Conference Conference (Hythe, Kent) -- First Conference Session, Jun 25, 1977 (Box 8)
    - News and the Law, Anglo-American Conference Conference (Hythe, Kent) -- Second Conference Session, Jun 25, 1977 (Box 8)
    - News and the Law, Anglo-American Conference Conference (Hythe, Kent) -- Third Conference Session, Jun 26, 1977 (Box 8)
    - News and the Law, Anglo-American Conference Conference (Hythe, Kent) -- Fourth Conference Session, Jun 26, 1977 (Box 8)
    - Media and Business Seminar (Princeton, NJ) -- First Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Nesson, Oct 8, 1977 (Box 8)
    - Media and Business Seminar (Princeton, NJ) -- Second Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Schmidt, Oct 8, 1977 (Box 8)
    - Media and Business Seminar (Princeton, NJ) -- Third and Fourth Conference Sessions -- Discussion Leaders, Miller and Fouraker, Oct 9, 1977 (Box 8)
    - National Conference on the Media and the Law (Princeton, NJ) -- First Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Miller, Nov 5, 1977 (Box 8)
    - National Conference on the Media and the Law (Princeton, NJ) -- Second Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Nesson, Nov 5, 1977 (Box 8)
    - National Conference on the Media and the Law (Princeton, NJ) -- Thrid Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Schmidt, Nov 6, 1977 (Box 8)
    - Philadelphia Conference on the Media and the Law -- First Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Nesson, Jan 14, 1978 (Box 8)
    - Philadelphia Conference on the Media and the Law -- Second Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Schmidt, Jan 14, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Philadelphia Conference on the Media and the Law -- Third Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Miller, Jan 15, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Tennessee Conference on the Media and the Law (Nashville, TN) -- First Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Miller, Mar 4, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Tennessee Conference on the Media and the Law (Nashville, TN) -- Second Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Nesson, Mar 4, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Tennessee Conference on the Media and the Law (Nashville, TN) -- Third Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Schmidt, Mar 5, 1978 (Box 9)
    - New England Business, Media and Law Seminar (Southbury, CT) -- First Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Nesson, May 13, 1978 (Box 9)
    - New England Business, Media and Law Seminar (Southbury, CT) -- Second Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Miller, May 13, 1978 (Box 9)
    - New England Business, Media and Law Seminar (Southbury, CT) -- Third Conference Session -- Discussion Leaders, Walter Salmon and Louis Banks, May 14, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Upstate New York Conference on the Media and the Law -- Discussion Leaders, Nesson, Schmidt, and Miller, Aug 5-6, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Seminar on Media, Government and the Law (New Delhi, India) -- Discussion Leader, Anthony Lester, Aug 26, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Conference on the Media and the Law (Hot Springs, VA) -- First Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Schmidt, Sep 15, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Conference on the Media and the Law (Hot Springs, VA) -- Second Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Miller, Sep 16, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Tri-State Regional Conference on the Media and the Law (Glen Cove, NY) -- First Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Nesson, Oct 14, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Tri-State Regional Conference on the Media and the Law (Glen Cove, NY) -- Second Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Miller, Oct 14, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Tri-State Regional Conference on the Media and the Law (Glen Cove, NY) -- Third Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Schmidt, Oct 15, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Akron Conference on the Media and the Law (Akron, OH) -- First Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Miller, Oct 28, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Akron Conference on the Media and the Law (Akron, OH) -- Second Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Nesson, Oct 28, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Akron Conference on the Media and the Law (Akron, OH) -- Third Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Schmidt, Oct 29, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Conference on Human Rights, Foreign Policy and the Media (Princeton, NJ) -- First Conference Session -- Moderator, Schmidt, Nov 4, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Conference on Human Rights, Foreign Policy and the Media (Princeton, NJ) -- Second Conference Session -- Moderator, Alan Dershowitz, Nov 4, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Conference on Human Rights, Foreign Policy and the Media (Princeton, NJ) -- "The Emergency, Censorship and the Press in India: A Retropsective", Nov 4, 1978 (Box 9)
    - Conference on Human Rights, Foreign Policy and the Media -- Third Conference Session -- Thomas Franck, Nov 5, 1978 (Box 10)
    - Northern California Conference on the Media and the Law (Carmel Valley, CA) -- First Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Schmidt, Dec 9, 1978 (Box 10)
    - Northern California Conference on the Media and the Law (Carmel Valley, CA) -- Second Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, John Kaplan, Dec 9, 1978 (Box 10)
    - Northern California Conference on the Media and the Law (Carmel Valley, CA) -- Third Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Miller, Dec 10, 1978 (Box 10)
    - Northern California Conference on the Media and the Law (Carmel Valley, CA) -- Summary -- Discussion Leader, Nesson, Dec 10, 1978 (Box 10)
    - Media and Business Seminar (Lake Bluff, IL) -- First Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Miller, Feb 3, 1979 (Box 10)
    - Media and Business Seminar (Lake Bluff, IL) -- Second Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Fred Friendly, Feb 3, 1979 (Box 10)
    - Media and Business Seminar (Lake Bluff, IL) -- Third Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Lawrence Lavengood, Feb 4, 1979 (Box 10)
    - National Seminar on State Courts and Public Policy -- First Conference Session -- Discussion Leaders, Nesson and Miller, May 4, 1979 (Box 10)
    - National Seminar on State Courts and Public Policy -- Second Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Miller, May 5, 1979 (Box 10)
    - National Seminar on State Courts and Public Policy -- Third Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Nesson, May 5, 1979 (Box 10)
    - National Seminar on State Courts and Public Policy -- Fourth Conference Session, Summary, and Closing Remarks -- Schmidt, Friendly, and Edward McConnell, May 6, 1979 (Box 10)
    - NDAA Conference, Media and the Law (Palm Springs, CA) -- Discussion Leader, Nesson, Dec 3, 1979 (Box 10)
    - Media and Government Conference (Hot Springs, VA) -- Don Graham, Friendly, Art Buchwald, Nesson, Mar 28-29, 1980 (Box 10)
    - Media and Government Conference (Hot Springs, VA) -- Third Conference Session -- Conference Leader, Schmidt, Mar 30, 1980 (Box 10)
    - Seminar on Broadcast Media and the Law (Cooperstown, NY) -- Discussion Leader, Schmidt, Jul 29, 1980 (Box 10)
    - Seminar on Broadcast Media and the Law (Cooperstown, NY) -- Discussion Leader, Miller, Jul 30, 1980 (Box 10)
    - Seminar on Broadcast Media and the Law (Cooperstown, NY) -- Discussion Leaders, Nesson and Friendly, Jul 30-31, 1980 (Box 10)
    - Michigan Conference on Business and the Media, Nov 10-11, 1980 (Box 10)
    - Conference on the Media and City Government (Princeton, NJ) -- First Conference Session -- Discussion Leader, Nesson and Opening Remarks, Nov 21-22, 1980 (Box 10)
    - Public Image Workshops, n.d. (Box 10)
    - Seminar on Human Rights -- Moderators, Dershowitz and Schmidt (Box 10)
    - Western Conference on the Media and Business (Box 10)
  - Fred Friendly Office Files -- Sesame Street Funding Correspondence, 1970; I.5
    - Letters Re: Ending Funding for Sesame Street (folder 1), Feb 1970 (Box 11)
    - Letters Re: Ending Funding for Sesame Street (folder 2), Feb 1970 (Box 11)
    - Letters Re: Ending Funding for Sesame Street (folder 3), Feb 1970 (Box 11)
    - Letters Re: Ending Funding for Sesame Street (folder 4), Feb 1970 (Box 11)
    - Letters Re: Ending Funding for Sesame Street (folder 5), Feb-Mar 1970 (Box 11)
- Kristin Anderson/Stuart Sucherman Office Files, 1970-1972; II
  - Arthur D. Little, Inc. CATV Study (Broadband Cable Network/BCN Study), 1972 (Box 12)
  - Chronological Corresondence File (Anderson/Sucherman), 1971 (Box 12)
  - Chronological Correspondence (Sucherman, copies?), 1971 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence (Kristin Anderson) -- Survey of Schools of Communications, 1971-1972 (Box 12)
  - Market Survey Forms, [1970] (Box 12)
  - Market Survey -- Top 100, [1970-1971] (Box 12)
  - CATV Markets, 1-13, 1970-1971 (Box 12)
  - CATV Markets, 14-25, 1970-1971 (Box 12)
  - CATV Markets, 26-39, 1970-1971 (Box 12)
  - CATV Markets, 40-50, 190-1971 (Box 12)
  - CATV Markets, 51-63, 1970-1971 (Box 12)
  - CATV Markets, 64-75, 1970-1971 (Box 12)
  - CATV Markets, 76-87, 1970-1971 (Box 12)
  - CATV Markets, 88-100, 1970-1971 (Box 12)
  - NCTA Convention, Jul 6-9, 1971 (Box 12)
  - "News and Public Affairs Workshop" -- Report (Chicago), Dec 14-15, 1970 (Box 12)
- David M. Davis Office Files, 1955-1971; III
  - David M. Davis Office Files -- Reports, 1962-1970
    - The Future of Educational Television, Dec 1962 (Box 13)
    - Report and Recommendations -- A National Noncommercial Television Service, Jun 1963 (Box 13)
    - Ford Foundation Planning Papers, Jun-Aug 1963 (Box 13)
    - The Hidden Medium: Educational Radio -- A Status Report, Apr 1967 (Box 13)
    - Learning by Television, May 1966 (Box 13)